<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://aestial.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://aestial.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><updated>2023-10-14T20:21:35+00:00</updated><id>https://aestial.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Jaime Hernandez’ site</title><subtitle>Computer engineer portfolio website to showcase ideas, jobs and experiments. </subtitle><entry><title type="html">Updating portfolio website</title><link href="https://aestial.github.io/blog/2023/updating-portfolio/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Updating portfolio website"/><published>2023-10-14T13:30:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-10-14T13:30:00+00:00</updated><id>https://aestial.github.io/blog/2023/updating-portfolio</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://aestial.github.io/blog/2023/updating-portfolio/"><![CDATA[<p>Today, I decided that there should be an easier and cheaper way to manage my personal website than hosting it on a shared server using Django, Postgres and DigitalOcean. Besides I didn’t really like the way of delivering content into the blog and other collections like uploading and reference media files through the database for mention some.</p> <p>For that reason, my former blog is almost unpopulated and in my humble opinion I’m wasting resources for the kind of web application that is hosted on all that infrastructure.</p> <blockquote> <p>:warning: WIP. This post is being updated through this job progress.</p> </blockquote>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="dev"/><category term="web"/><category term="portfolio"/><category term="gh-pages"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Experience updating personal portfolio website, the lazy way.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Death of Unity Engine</title><link href="https://aestial.github.io/blog/2023/unity-death/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Death of Unity Engine"/><published>2023-09-18T12:01:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-09-18T12:01:00+00:00</updated><id>https://aestial.github.io/blog/2023/unity-death</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://aestial.github.io/blog/2023/unity-death/"><![CDATA[<blockquote> <p>Updates on license policy and fees got developers mad at Unity’s headquarters.</p> </blockquote> <p>In the ever-evolving world of game development, what once held the promise of being a tool for the masses, opening the doors to game creation for everyone, has taken an unexpected turn.</p> <p>Back in the early days, Unity played a pivotal role in building a vibrant community around game development. It catapulted itself into the mainstream, and those who wielded its powers were elevated to legendary status among aspiring developers and artists. Unity became the stage where creators transformed into digital rockstars, using its tools to craft captivating gaming experiences.</p> <p>Yet, as history has shown, even the mightiest empires, including those in the realm of technology, eventually face challenges. Unity’s unchallenged dominance in the world of game engines has reached a turning point. The community now grapples with a fresh challenge: the need to break free from Unity’s protective embrace, the very entity that initiated this creative revolution.</p> <p>Unity, as a company, has embarked on a profound mission—to extend the ideals of democratization to other game engines, making sure they’re just as appealing and accessible as Unity itself once was. It’s a shift toward embracing diversity and choice in game development, ensuring that developers and artists aren’t confined to a single engine’s toolkit.</p> <p>In this transformative journey, Artificial Intelligence (AI) emerges as a trusted ally. AI lends a helping hand to developers and artists, offering solutions that simplify the creative process. It can provide instant feedback, suggest optimizations, and even assist in generating game content, making the game development process more intuitive and efficient.</p> <p>The time has come for the game development community, both seasoned Unity veterans and newcomers alike, to shift their perspective. It’s an era of collective growth and maturity, a moment where Unity might need to gracefully step aside to make way for fresh innovations and alternatives, with AI as a friendly companion in this creative voyage. This juncture marks an opportunity for Unity, in its current form, to evolve, adapt, or even gracefully step into history, all in the name of paving the path for a more diverse and democratized game development landscape.</p> <p>In conclusion, the evolution of Unity and the broader world of game development tools represents an exciting chapter in our creative journey. It’s not just about an engine; it’s a story of an industry evolving to meet the demands of a diverse community of developers and artists. Unity’s journey, whether it continues to lead or graciously yields the spotlight, remains pivotal in shaping the future of game development—an ongoing quest driven by the values of diversity, choice, and the relentless pursuit of innovation, with AI as a trusted companion along the way.</p> <hr/> <h4 id="more-on-this">More on this</h4> <ul> <li><a href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/the-death-of-unity">The Death of Unity</a></li> <li><a href="https://fortune.com/2023/09/14/unity-closes-offices-death-threat/">Unity closes 2 offices after receiving death threat - Fortune</a></li> </ul> <div class="caption"> Vlogers opinion on Unity's Death or The Death of Unity. </div> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/1zuZaJE3n-4?si=Va_r_mftZG6RG75R" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen="" width="auto" height="auto"/> </figure> </div> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/sxU5XwDuo2Y?si=mijaqNe-7bGC6oyI" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen="" width="auto" height="auto"/> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> Some history on Unity and it's role on Game Development </div> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Duo0kC1IitU?si=ef28cOpYDAQXQmBL" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen="" width="auto" height="auto"/> </figure> </div> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ZJ8fzanm4_0?si=I3yWKoxjmA6B7iYd" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen="" width="auto" height="auto"/> </figure> </div> </div> <hr/> <h4 id="godot-on-x-twitter">Godot on X (Twitter)</h4> <p>Get some inspiration on my favorite Open Source Unity alternative:</p> <div class="jekyll-twitter-plugin"><a class="twitter-timeline" data-width="500" data-tweet-limit="3" href="https://twitter.com/godotengine?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">Tweets by godotengine</a> <script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script> </div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="opinion"/><category term="news"/><category term="review"/><category term="unity"/><category term="publishing"/><category term="update"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[My two cents on new Unity's license policy.]]></summary></entry></feed>